Joining tables is not always sufficient to solve a problem.
The exercise you just completed was a demonstration that union allows you to combine the result set
of two select statements.
So remember this trick because you are often needed at your workplace.
Another interesting school tool worth remembering is the self-join it is applied when a table must join
itself.
This is not a rare event.
If you'd like to combine certain rows of a table with other rows of the same table you need a self-join
to better understand the mechanics of this Escudo instrument.
Look at the following visualization.
Think of a case in which you are joining two tables.
Previously we saw how this is done with different tables in a self join statement.
You will have to comply with the same logical and syntactic structure.
However the two tables will be identical to the table you'll be using in the self-join you can think
of them as virtual projections of the underlying base table.
OK good.
So the self-join will reference both implied tables and will treat them as two separate tables in its
operations.
Furthermore the data used will not come from two sources but from a single source which is the underlying
table that stores data physically
great.
Earlier when we joined separate tables using aliases was at our discretion.
It was done mainly for convenience here using aliases is obligatory only they can help us distinguish
the two virtual tables.
But here comes the tricky part.
These references to the original table let you use different blocks of the available data.
You can either filter both in the join or you can filter one of them in the WHERE clause and the other
one in the join.
If this sounds strange Please don't worry we will provide examples of both cases later in this lecture.
So our task is from the employee manager table created in the previous exercise.
Extract the record data.
Only of those employees who are managers as well
OK.
Observing the table obtained
we can expect to have only two rows affected by our query
nice.
Let's look at the code we are using the structure of the JOIN syntax.
Also we are joining the same table to itself providing different aliases for each virtual table.
However the connection is made with different columns of the base table and we would like to extract
everything from the first table provided that its employee number equals the manager number of the other
table.
Let's run this query and observe the output
Wow 42 rows.
What happened.
The query connected the employee numbers of the first table coinciding with managing numbers with the
records from the manager number column of the second table.
So we have two records from the left side 1 1 0 0 22 and 1 1 0 0 39 connected to 42 records on the right
side having the same values.
So why do you see 22 against 39 and 39 against 22 and not something else.
Here's the explanation.
Every time a connection between two implied tables is established all data of the corresponding row
of the left table is displayed.
For instance whenever we have 1 1 0 0 or 22 in the second table only column data from the first table
is being recorded in a new table.
This means the manager number column information is not taken from E to
then the same process is repeated for the other manager.
Number 1 1 0 0 THIRTY-NINE fine.
What will happen if we change the table in the select statement to eat to logically we will retrieve
42 connections again but this time the data displayed will refer solely to table e to and not e one
clear.
What if you would like to obtain a result containing employee number and apartment number from each
one and manager number from E to.
To do that you will have to adjust the selection retrieved by the execution of your query.
Set the first two columns to be extracted from the left virtual table and the third one from the right.
Is this going to work.
Of course it will.
That's fantastic.
Unfortunately we have not solved our problem yet.
How can we obtain two rows of data in our result.
There are two ways to do that.
The first way is simply by using Select Distinct instead of select then applying the same code we used
at the beginning of the lecture thus all repeating rows from the first queery will be stacked and we
will see only the two desired records.
The second way is more sophisticated.
We will use the same base query that would lead us to the 42 row output.
But this time a WHERE clause will be added
and its condition will shorten the length of e two to two rows.
Why would we do that.
Because this creates a connection of the employee number from each one that isn't with all 42 rows from
the manager number column of e to.
But with two rows only
a ha makes sense.
And how do we do that.
By using the in operator to state we want the employee number column from the second virtual table to
equal any of the manager numbers from the base table.
In other words the where sub query regarding this small two row table
OK.
Good
execute the query and
perfect the desired output was obtained.
Phew.
Everything seems so complicated at the beginning but now we saw that using self joins isn't an impossible
task is it.
Please complete the exercises to strengthen the knowledge you just acquired here.
Thank you for watching.