We started this course by presenting a brief introduction to Eskew Well theory.
We continued by explaining how tables can be created and how to use the insert statement.
Later we learned how to create tables.
You were able to set up the entire cell's database on your own.
Remember that's awesome.
Now in this section we are ready to explore the insert statement in a bit more detail.
Let's practice inserting a few records in the Employees table.
We can extract 10 records from the Employees table to see all the information is organized there.
Please allow me to make the following remark in the last lecture.
We increase the limit of rows displayed in an output to infinity.
So in the queries in this lecture I will place limits through the limit clause great.
So execute and ha nice.
We retrieved 10 rows all containing information in the following columns.
Employee number birth date first and last name gender and hire date.
A total of six columns.
OK let's see how to create a record in the Employees table after the key word phrase insert into.
We must specify the name of the table where we went to add information.
Then within parentheses we must indicate the column names where data will be inserted.
Please pay attention.
You don't have to use the names of all six columns you can designate only those in which you would like
to insert data.
What follows is intuitive.
The values keyword succeeded by the same number of data values as the number of columns indicated in
the parentheses after the insert into statement.
Know that the data values should be typed within parentheses to.
You are already acquainted with the syntax we just discussed.
Now let's put it into practice.
Will create a record of an individual named John Smith will type insert into employees and then within
parentheses specify the columns we want to add information into separating them by a comma.
These columns are employee number birth date first name last name gender and hire date then after the
keyword values and within parentheses type the data values that will be part of these columns again
separating them by a comma to see the Data Types of the values you will insert.
You must check the data types of this table's fields.
You can do this by going to the information section and looking at the data types in the columns tab.
The employee number is an integer.
Then you have to date values to var char values and an ENM.
Therefore as you insert the new records all values must be written in single quotes.
Besides the employee number
great let's assign the number 9 9 9 9 0 1 and a birth date of the 21st of April 1986
This record will refer to John Smith.
M.
who is hired on the 1st of January 2011
to register this row in the data table will need to execute the insert query.
All right we see that we have one row affected.
Now let's select the 10 employees with the largest employee numbers to see if our record will appear
there.
Awesome.
Here he is John Smith is on the top.
Let me comment on this bizarre number 9 9 9 9 0 1.
Obviously this is not the next consecutive number in our super long list of employees is it.
Remember that using such an employee number is a neat professional trick.
When data is being created to test the database system the value inserted should be quite high.
This way it is obvious where the new data has been placed.
For this reason we saw John Smith on the top of the employee's list with the highest employee number
OK.
Great.
Let's move on now.
Let me share another my will feature with you.
Contrary to anything we've said so far it turns out that integers can be written within quotes too.
If you wish you can try inserting another record with the employee number within quotes you'll see the
data is still registered as an integer.
The explanation why is that my ask you will will automatically or some professionals would say transparently
convert the string into an integer.
The best practice is to avoid writing integers with in quotes.
Since this conversion consumes time and prevents the smooth operation of more advanced minuscule features
to conclude the idea is that yes you could write an integer with in quotes but this is not considered
a best practice.
That's why we would like to give you the following piece of advice.
Please remember to type integers as plain numbers without using quotes great.
Let's keep up the pace for our next video.
See you there.