Okay perfect Let's go ahead with the insert clause usually database administrators follow the order
of columns in terms of the way they appear in a given data table.
However on certain occasions they prefer inserting data values in a different order.
My Eskew Well allows for such types of data insertion.
For instance should we create a data record about Patricia Lawrence.
We would insert her birth date first then her employee number and then site the rest of the values in
the designated order.
Let's see if it works.
100 percent.
The last row we created contains information about Patricia Laurent's.
So please keep in mind that we must put the values in the exact order we have listed the column names
fantastic OK.
Let's take a look at an interesting feature of the insert syntax.
Technically the first pair of parentheses along with the column names between them can be omitted.
Only insert into the table name and the values parts are mandatory.
If you omitted in the values section you will have to specify as many data values as there are columns
in the data table.
Furthermore you will have to add them in the same order in which they appear in the table.
For example if we use this structure and try to create a record in the Employees table with only four
instead of six columns my rescue will will display an error if we try to add six data values to the
new record.
All of them in the correct order.
The query should work fine.
Let's check
good the new piece of information is there in the next video we will show you a very powerful feature
of the insert statement that will do for now.
Thanks for watching.