Right.
So in this lesson we will show you another way to insert data into a table.
The relevant syntax is insert into table name and column names in parentheses.
Then comes the new part.
You can use a classical select statement to retrieve information from some other table and inserted
into this table here.
It doesn't have to be the entire table from that other table by using where you should be able to set
conditions that would refine the data to be copied.
Let's see an example.
First check the columns of the department's table.
We have two columns department code and department name.
So the next thing to do is create another table called deps duplicate.
Shortening it to departments underscore d'you see it will be a replica of the department's table.
We just saw here our task is to import all the data from departments into its duplicate OK.
The code will need to create the copy table is create table departments duplicate open parentheses department
number char type of four not no constraint added Then department name var char 40 not constrain again
close parentheses execute and then refresh the schema section and workbench.
Here we are.
The new table has been added to the list.
Furthermore the department number and department name columns are visible to great to verify that this
is still an empty table.
We have to select all the information from it.
You see there is no information.
Now is the time to implement the structure we introduced in this lecture.
We will insert into the department number and department name columns from the department's duplicate
table.
Everything we can select from the department's table.
Please note that since deps contains the same number and type of columns it is not necessary to add
specific conditions to the data retrieved from the table.
Hence the star wildcard character will do the job properly right.
So let's run this query OK.
The code was executed with no errors.
Let's see if the operation was performed correctly.
It was most definitely we see that the newly created departments duplicate table has been filled with
information from the departments table.
That's awesome.
In other words our job is done.
I'd like to wrap up this lecture with a reminder about my Majeski Well constraints we barely mentioned
them in this section.
However you know that unless the new data you are inserting satisfies the constraints that have already
been set in the database my S Q Will will always show an error.
For simplicity we carefully designed our code and such errors were avoided.
In other words we ensured we did not insert data that does not satisfy the existing constraints.
Nevertheless keep in mind that complying with constraints is essential.
They will always play a major role when inserting data.
I hope you enjoyed the lectures from this short section.
Thank you for watching.