Now that you know what a relational database is and have an idea about how it works, it is much easier
to understand how SQL fits in the whole picture. SQL is the programming language you need
to execute commands that let you create and manipulate a relational database.
We will not delve into strict and detailed technical definitions to explain how it works.
What you need to know is there are a few types of programming out there - procedural (imperative), object-
oriented, declarative, and functional. Although with some procedural elements, SQL is mainly regarded
as a declarative programming language, it is non procedural.
This means while coding you will not be interested in how you want the job done.
The focus is on what results you want to obtain.
An abstract example would best clarify what we mean here.
When using a procedural language, such as C or Java, you must explicitly divide the solution of a certain
problem into several steps.
For instance: 1. Please open the door. 2. Go outside 3.
Take the bucket.
I forgot there. 4. Bring it back to me.
In a declarative language, this would sound like:
1. Fetch the bucket, please.
And you wouldn't have to go through the process step by step.
The algorithms are built-in, and there is an optimizer, which will separate your task into smaller steps
and do the magic to bring the desired output.
Why is this important? When using SQL,
you should concentrate on what you want to retrieve from your databases.
Unless you are an advanced user, don't bother with the algorithms explaining how your data can be obtained.
Acknowledging SQL is principally a declarative language,
now we can go through the main components of its syntax.
It comprises a Data Definition Language (known as DDL), a data manipulation language (abbreviated DML), a data
control language (DCL), and a transaction control language (TCL).
These will be the topics of our next few videos.
Thank you for watching!