When working in real-life, not every change you make to a database is saved automatically;
you have to say you wish that to happen.
The statement to use in such cases is COMMIT.
It works only for changes made with the help of the INSERT, DELETE, or UPDATE clauses. COMMIT will save
the changes you've made permanently on the database and will let other users have access to the modified
version of the database.
For instance imagine you have updated a record in the "customers" table.
Say you wish to change the last name of the fourth customer from Winnfield to Johnson.
If you are an administrator, you can do that with the help of the UPDATE clause, and you will see "Johnson"
appear in the place of "Winnfield". The UPDATE statement we saw earlier would allow you to change the last
name of the fourth customer.
However, your work isn't done just yet.
The rest of the users working with the database system cannot see you have made any changes. To complete
the entire process,
you must add a COMMIT statement at the end of the UPDATE block.
Only then will the updated information be available to all users -
they will see Catherine Johnson, not Catherine Winnfield, as customer number 4 in the "Customers" table.
Committed States can accrue.
If you are a database administrator, you might need to use COMMIT 20 times per day.
The Transaction Control Language clause that will let you make a step back and restore the database
to the last committed state is ROLLBACK.
This allows you to undo any changes you have made but don't want to be saved permanently. To apply this
command, type ROLLBACK;
Be careful when using this statement, because it will revert to the last committed state, and all the changes
made in the meantime will be removed.
There can be multiple statements executed, and they will all be undone.
To recap, COMMIT saves the transaction in the database;
once issued, the changes are saved permanently, and they cannot be undone.
ROLLBACK allows you to take a step back, and the last change, or changes, you've made, will not count.
ROLLBACK reverts to the last non-committed state.
If you wonder why we went through the syntax in relative detail, you can think of the following explanation.
The DDL, DML, DCL, and TCL statements are for separate parts of the SQL syntax that represent what
the language can be used for: creation and manipulation of data, assignment and removal of permissions
to use this data, and saving and restoring changes to a database.
These lectures served well to give you a good overall technical idea of why SQL is used widely across
companies and institutions around the world.
In the next section, we will learn more about database theory and will ensure that, by the end of this
course, you will have the solid practical and theoretical knowledge that allows you to work proficiently
in SQL.
Thanks for watching!