All right! Good! Let's go over the components of SQL's syntax.
It comprises several types of statements that allow you to perform various commands and operations.
The Data Definition Language, DDL, is one type.
It is called a language but you can think of it as a syntax, a set of statements that allow the user
to define or modify data structures in objects such as tables. One DDL statement is the CREATE statement.
As its name suggests, it is used for creating entire databases and database objects as tables.
For example, if we want to create a table, we must abide by the following syntax: CREATE TABLE, object name,
column name, and data type in parentheses and semi-column. As expected, the CREATE statement creates
an object with a certain name.
In this case, we are creating a table. Given we have to assign columns to the table, after specifying the
table name within parentheses,
we must also indicate the names of the columns and the type of data contained in each column.
Look at this example. With this line of code,
you can create a table with the name "Sales", containing one column, called "purchase number", that will store
only integer values.
Easy, right?
Don't worry if the table name coincides with the name we've assigned to the database.
This is a common practice. On one hand,
the syntax will make it clearer when you refer to the database and to the table.
On the other hand, it is logical it makes sense for a database to bear the same name as its main table.
Ok. Great!
Observe how simple the syntax of the CREATE statement is -
you will have to write it at the beginning of the line and then directly point out the type and name
of the object.
Awesome!
And why did we start with an example where we created a table and not some other object?
Because it helps us understand better how the ALTER statement works which is the operation to be carried
out when altering existing objects.
For example, we can use ALTER to modify a table by adding, removing, or renaming one of the columns in
the table. To add a column, called "date of purchase",
you should begin with the same structure as the one used for the CREATE statement. After ALTER,
You will be able to designate the object type and its name.
After that you are supposed to write down the precise modification.
This means a new column containing the date of the purchase will be added to our table.
In addition, the values in this column will be of the DATE type. Intuitive, right?
What if you want to delete a database object?
In that case, you can use the DROP statement to do that.
For instance, we can delete the entire "Customers" table with a single line of code:
DROP TABLE "Customers". As you can see, the DDL statement was accompanied by the object type and its name.
Another valuable tool when using the Data Definition Language is RENAME. This piece of syntax allows
you to rename an object like a database table.
If we hadn't dropped that "Customers" table, RENAME TABLE "Customers" to "Customer Data" would have changed
the name of the table to "Customer Data". Ok!
Finally, instead of deleting an entire table through DROP, we can also remove its data and continue to
have the table as an object in the database.
In such a situation, TRUNCATE is the DDL statement that would allow us to do that.
After executing this clause, all the records from the "Customers" table will be deleted but, although empty,
the table will continue to exist. As a quick recap of this lesson,
remember the Data Definition Language constitutes the part of the SQL syntax that allows you to create, alter,
drop, rename, and truncate databases and their elements.
Once you have created a database with its elements and have loaded it with information, you are ready
to step up to the next level and manipulate the data to obtain various statistics or other tables that
will help you solve your business analytical problems.
To do this, you will have to get acquainted with the syntax of the Data Manipulation Language.
Stay tuned.