Let's stop for a quick side note. ADD is a keyword,
and so are CREATE and ALTER. For instance, keywords in SQL cannot be variable names.
Think of them as words that constitute the language. The software you are using will understand which
commands and operations you wish to carry out,
namely through these words. To avoid any confusion for the software, objects or databases cannot have
names that coincide with SQL keywords. To exemplify,
think of all one-word statements like CREATE an ALTER.
They are keywords. So, you can't call your table "alter",
since this is a name that can trigger a certain process -
the modification of the content of a designated
table.
So, back to our example, ADD is the keyword that will add a column, called "Date of Purchase", in the "Sales"
It is one of the keywords frequently used with the ALTER statement.
Finally, don't get confused if you hear the term reserved words.
It is a synonym for keywords, which indicates precisely what we explained;
these words cannot be used when naming objects.
Ok. So that's about it for keywords.
Thank you for watching!