Now that we know more about DDL and some of its arguments, we are ready to focus on DML, the Data Manipulation
Language. In particular, we will learn about some statements that allow us to manipulate the data in the
tables of a database.
We will start with SELECT, a statement used to retrieve data from database objects, like tables.
The star after the select statement in the following line will deliver the entire content of the "sales"
table, meaning all records and fields contained in the table.
You can use the same structure to extract specific records from the table but at this point one could
rightly ask: What for? - We can see the entire table here.
Why are we going to need just a piece of it?
Well imagine a table with two million rows of data.
You can only see a small part of it on the screen,
right?
This is why it can be helpful if you could extract only a portion of the table that satisfies given
criteria.
This is crucial and is one of the most powerful tools available in SQL. You should know how to
use SELECT perfectly well, so you designate the precise area of the table
you would like to extract information from with ease. In this course,
Many lessons in exercises include this statement.
So, by the end, you will feel confident when using it and selecting a certain part of a database.
INSERT is used to insert data into tables.
It enables you to add more records or rows while you are working with the table.
This clause goes hand in hand with the keywords INTO and VALUES.
In the parentheses, after the table name,
you will have to specify the columns you are adding information to,
unless you want to insert data in all columns.
For the moment, our "Sales" table contains only two fields,
so if we want to add purchase number and date values, we could omit the part with column names in parentheses,
and our statement would look like this:
The two versions are identical. Syntactically, such statement makes sense, because it allows you to insert
values right into a table.
This line of code allows you to register the first record of the dataset.
It will appear as the first row of the cells table.
This code will add another record - purchase number 2 and the date 27th of October 2017.
Amazing! So far,
we saw how to select and insert information in SQL. Remember,
you can also update information. UPDATE allows you to renew existing data of your tables.
Its syntax is slightly different and is best understood with an example.
This piece of code will allow us to substitute the previously inserted date of purchase number 1,
11th of October 2017, with the ones specified here,
12th of December 2017.
And how do we get to this date the 11th of October?
The update is based on the number of the purchase -  purchase number 1. This way, the entire row is updated,
and the date will be 12th of December 2017.
There is one additional DML clause I would like to show you in this lesson.
It is DELETE. It function similarly to the TRUNCATE statement from the Data Definition Language with
one substantial difference.
TRUNCATE allows us to remove all the records contained in a table; with DELETE,
you can specify precisely what you would like to be removed.
For instance, the following phrase will remove all the records from the "sales" table just as if we had
written TRUNCATE TABLE sales;
If we take advantage of the optional WHERE clause, instead, the following statement will delete the record
with a purchased number of one, and the other one we have in our miniature table will be left intact.
Our table will remain only with the second record -
The one with purchase number two and date of purchase 27th of October 2017.
To summarize, the Data Manipulation Language syntax is composed mainly of the following four elements
containing statements and keywords:
SELECT... FROM...,
INSERT INTO... VALUES..., UPDATE SET... WHERE..., and DELETE... FROM... and optionally WHERE. In our next video, we'll learn
what part of SQL's syntax is referred to as Data Control Language.
Thank you!