Hello and welcome to our SQL course! I am Martin and I am a programmer who has spent significant time
working with SQL and databases.
It is my pleasure to present a course that stands out from the rest of the SQL courses available
on Udemy and online.
This course is different, because we will not repeat everything written in one of the textbooks about
SQL and relational databases.
Instead I will provide you with the set of SQL practical tools you will need at your workplace.
No useless concepts.
Everything is straight to the point and easy to understand.
The curriculum we have prepared for you comprises a heterogeneous set of topics data analysts and data
managers need in their daily work. SQL allows these professionals to manipulate large sets of data.
An advantage of using SQL is its syntax is intuitive, which predisposes you to learn it quickly.
You'll first need to internalize the meaning of a few specific terms if you want to grasp the wide
scope of its application and the ease with which this language can solve sophisticated tasks.
Therefore, in the first part of this course, we will focus on explaining databases, database management
systems, and SQL.
I have organized the videos so the abstract ideas are easy to understand.
No, this will not be a set of boring theoretical SQL concepts you'll never hear at your workplace.
This is precisely the knowledge you need to understand how to work with data, tables, relational database
management systems, and their visual representation!
Before we start, I would like to ask a favor.
Do not skip any of the lectures in the first part!
I promise they will help you develop the perfect orientation and logical reasoning required for smooth,
high-quality coding throughout the course.
After the first part, we'll show you how to setup the software environment you'll need in this course,
and you'll be able to roll up your sleeves and start programming.
The best part is you won't just see how you can work with an existing database.
We will show you how to create an entirely new database from scratch!
That's great, right?
Just wait to hear what comes after that.
In this course, we will work with a real-world database from GitHub.
It is large enough and will give you a good idea of how we can use SQL in real-life situations.
It is not a small data set gathered for a beginners' course.
I am sure you will appreciate this aspect of the course.
We believe this is the right way to learn as well.
Then, after you learn how to set up a database on your own, you will plunge into the wonderful world of
data manipulation.
This is the section where you will learn how powerful SQL can be when used for the extraction of
information and insights from a database.
You'll go through:
- the classical SQL statements
- column and table constraints
- functions.
Then, we will cover more sophisticated topics such as:
- joins
- subqueries
- self-joins
- views.
Finally, we'll be ready to learn how to work with some tools professionals love to
use: stored procedures and functions.
We will conclude the course by learning about a few challenging advanced SQL techniques, such as
triggers and indexes.
Besides the fundamentals, this course will teach you a solid set of useful topics, tips, tricks, and sharp
skills that will give you an edge in the market.
I am a firm believer in the statement: 'the most effective way to learn is by doing'.
This is valid especially for SQL, because the difficulty of the tasks you must deal with at work
require previous experience.
So, please do the exercises attached to the lectures!
They will be in the form of quiz questions
and will reinforce everything you have learned in the lessons.
Should you have any queries, please reach out and write in the Q&A section.
We will be happy to answer within one or two business days.
In addition, throughout the course and in my practice, I stick to best practices and clean coding.
Remember, a well organized, or good code, is not the one
computers can understand.
It is the one
humans can understand.
So... what are you waiting for?
Dive straight in and let's begin this journey together!