So... why study SQL?
Put yourself in the shoes of an employee or a manager of a company who works with large amounts of data.
For example, you could be working in Business Intelligence (BI), data science, database administration,
or back-end web development.
Any of these jobs relate to storing large amounts of data.
Therefore, before carrying out any analysis with the data, you will have to retrieve it.
As a consequence, the focus of our course is namely on developing the skills required to solve business
analytical problems and applying solutions in a software that allows you to extract the desired information
from the database. To achieve all this, you need SQL.
SQL means Structured Query Language.
It is a programming language specifically designed for working with databases.
It allows you to create, manipulate, and share data, especially data from relational database management
systems.
The way to tell the computer to extract information from the database for you is by writing queries
in SQL. A query, pronounced 'query' or 'querry', is a piece of code
inducing the computer to execute a certain operation that will deliver the desired output.
The latter process is called querying the database.
Briefly, SQL is the language that allows you to
write queries that the computer can execute and then provide database insights in return.
The good thing about SQL is it is an intuitive and easy-to-learn language.
Be careful, as this does not mean using it will be a simple task -
not at all!
Sometimes, the business problems you must solve will be peculiar and will involve the processing of large
amounts of data. Despite being relatively simple in its structure, SQL can be powerful while computing
very complex tasks.
This is why in this course we provide the raw skills you'll need to become a web programmer, a data analyst,
a data scientist, or a business intelligence analyst.
The idea is to combine video lessons and advanced exercises that will show you SQL is cool and fun
to work with!
And, if for some strange reason, you're still wondering whether SQL as a programming language worth
having in your skillset,
Let me show you the following statistics.
A Techworm study shows as well as the most demanded programming language for 2017
(in general not in a specific sector).
Indeed.com share the same information for 2016.
Indeed.com also ranks SQL high when related to lucrative job positions.
It is true.
Sometimes, these kinds of studies are indeed biased.
So, let's change the question and refer to a study conducted by Stack Overflow, where they asked over
56,000 developers in 173 countries "Which are the most used technologies?"
The top three are:
1. JavaScript - 55.4%
2. SQL - 49.1%
3. Java -
36.3%.
Therefore, SQL is a highly-demanded skill on the job market, no matter how you look at it.
Stay tuned for the next video to understand what it is and why it is the most suitable software environment
for this course.
Thanks for watching!