OK, so... at this point you might be telling yourself: Great Let me install a software containing SQL and
start the course.
Unfortunately, it is not so simple. Why? To implement SQL commands,
you will need a database management system, often called a database or a platform.
The problem is there are a few popular databases out there, which are all based on SQL. They support
various forms of the original language and there are only slight differences between different versions.
As a developer, you want to learn how to use the one that is the most suitable for your situation.
We will base our course entirely on MySQL,
but you should know there are other platforms like Oracle, SQLite, Microsoft SQL Server,
postscripts sequel.
Maria DB, Microsoft Access, and so on.
The minor differences between the versions of the SQL language mean that transferring from one database
to the other (which usually happens if your changing jobs) would not be an obstacle for you.
If you are a user of another platform, you can still take this course and easily apply the tools we teach.
So, why do we choose MySQL? Because it is reliable mature and open source.
The latter means it is free.
It is used by many institutions and companies, including Facebook YouTube, Dropbox, Twitter, Pinterest, Booking.com
and LinkedIn.
Considering the well-renowned DB-Engines Ranking, MySQL comes as the first open-source relational
database management system. Yes,
Oracle is on top with only a slight advantage,
but don't forget it is a paid software!
Therefore, aiming at providing you with the best experience possible,
we chose MySQL.
Now let's dig into some Database and SQL theory.
This will provide the set of tools you'll need when we deal with various SQL tasks in the lessons
to come.
Thanks for watching!