Up to now we have learned how to insert and update data in our tables in this section.
We will focus on removing records from a database.
This operation is carried out with the delete statement following what we said in the previous section
regarding commit and rollback.
And knowing that in this lecture we are bound to delete items.
We will start by executing a commit thus we will store the current state of our database if necessary
we will be able to revert to it later using rollback.
Right.
So in the lectures about insert and in the exercises attached to it under employee number 9 9 9 9 0
3 you added some information about Jonathan Creek.
Let's select his record in the Employees table.
Fine.
We can see his birth date Jinder and hire date.
OK.
Now let's see what information is contained about the same employee in the titles table
excellent his job position is senior engineer and he started working on the first of October 1997.
The lack of information in the to date column suggests that he is still working at the company good
as we mentioned at the beginning of the course the syntax to abide by when deleting information is delete
from table name and where with a corresponding condition in our case the code would be delete from employees
where employee number is 9 9 9 9 0 3.
What should happen when we run this query is that only the row with Employee Number 9 9 9 9 0 3 will
be removed.
Let's see if this is true.
After executing this delete statement then selecting the record from the Employees table providing the
same condition in the WHERE clause.
So what output will show up to an empty record.
This means we have properly deleted the information about Jonathan Creek.
Awesome.
What do you think.
Can we still see he was a senior engineer hired in October 1997.
We'll have to check what's left in the titles table
I'm empty as well.
Why didn't we order delete command for only the Employees table.
The answer lies in the connection between the two tables.
When we checked the DDL information about the titles table we see in the foreign key constraint that
we also have an on daily cascade clause in our earlier lecture.
We explained the meaning of this clause using it means all related records in the child table will be
deleted as well.
Fantastic.
For the sake of exercise assume we deleted Jonathan's information by mistake.
Is there a way we can go back considering that we apply to commit statement at the beginning of the
lecture then.
Yes there is.
We should be able to run a rollback command let's execute it
OK.
And now let's verify that the record has been put back in the table.
It's in the Employees table.
OK.
And
we have it entitles to perfect.
So our last comment did a good job preserving the full data set.
The initial large data set along with the three records we added in the insert section keep up the pace
for the next video in which we'll show you something with which you must be very careful.
Thank you for watching.