In this lesson we'll show you an unsafe delete operation if we do not set a condition in the WHERE clause
of a delete statement.
We are taking a big risk.
This could potentially lead to the removal of all the tables records.
That's why we must be very careful when using this statement always let's recall what we have in the
department's duplicate table the numbers and names of nine departments in the company.
Let's execute a delete statement without a WHERE clause attached to it.
You see nine rows were affected.
Now we can check the table once more.
It couldn't be emptier than that to undo the changes we should be able to execute a rollback statement.
OK.
And did it work.
We'll have to select all the information from this tiny table to verify whether we have our data back.
Here it is waiting to be retrieved.
Therefore in conclusion we can say the following.
Be careful with the delete statement.
Don't forget to attach a condition in the WHERE clause unless you want to lose all your information
in the next video.
We will compare drop delete and truncate.
See you there.