In this video we will briefly discuss the main difference between three reserved words drop truncate
and delete their functionality is similar.
And you might wonder why all of them and not just one exist.
Look at this hypothetical table with 10 records.
If you drop it you will lose the records.
The table has a structure and all related objects like indexes and constraints.
You will lose everything.
Furthermore you won't be able to roll back to its initial state or to the last commit statement.
Once you drop a table it's gone.
Only additional data recovery software will help in such a situation.
But it is not considered a standard eschewing tool.
Hence use drop table only when you're sure you aren't going to use the table in question any more truncate
is a statement that will essentially remove all records from the table just as if you had to use delete
without a WHERE clause.
This means truncate will remove all records in your table but its structure will remain intact.
Please bear in mind that when truncating auto increment values will be reset so if your table is 10
record records and then you truncate it when you start refilling this data object with information the
next records that will be inserted are not going to be 11 and 12.
The first record will be number one.
The second record will be number two thirds will and so on
nice finally delete removes records row by row only the rows corresponding to a certain condition or
conditions specified in the WHERE clause will be deleted.
If the where block is omitted the output will resemble the one obtained with truncate.
There will be a couple of significant distinctions though.
First the optimizer will implement different program Maddock approaches when we are using truncate or
delete as a result.
Truncate delivers the output much quicker than delete because it does not need to remove information
row by row.
Second autoincrement values are not reset with delete.
So if you delete all 10 records in this table and then start inserting new data the first new record
will be numbered 11 and not one.
The second will be 12 and not 2 and so on.
There are many other technical peculiarities regarding these three options but their detailed explanation
is beyond the scope of this course.
Nevertheless we hope this short lecture will help you make a more educated choice among drop truncate
and delete don't skip the exercises attached to this lecture.
Then fasten your seatbelts as the next set of lectures is about the Cuil functions.
Are you excited.
Good.
Let's dive right in.