In this lesson we'll talk about my rescue well use this as a tool that is tricky at first grasping its
functionality to the fullest can be a bit difficult without significant practice.
In this lecture we will introduce you to this concept and show you how and why viewers are used in S..
Q Well great a view is a virtual table whose contents are obtained from an existing table or tables
called base tables.
The retrieval happens through an executable statement incorporated into the view to remember this explanation
more easily.
Think of a view object as a view into the base table.
The view itself does not contain any real data.
The data is physically stored in the base table.
The view simply shows the data contained in the base table.
Let's provide an example and then we'll discuss when views can be helpful.
We will focus on the department employee table that contains information about the department in which
each employee is working as well as the start and end date of their contract.
It has more than 331 thousand entries.
OK some employee numbers have been inserted more than once.
Why.
Because a new entry about the same employee has been recorded every time the employee changed departments.
This results in more than one start and end date for such employees to verify this is the case.
We could run a query that shows the employee numbers of people registered in the department employee
table.
More than once after we executed we will know how many such entries we have 31000.
579.
Good.
Why would we need a view in this case well.
Imagine you wanted to see a tabular output with the number of each employee shown only once having aside
their latest starting and ending date.
In other words you would like to visualize only the period in compassing the last contract of each employee.
The syntax to abide by is the following.
First type.
Create or replace.
Of course.
Create view could suffice but the.
Or replace fragment ascertains that the code we are about to write will be executed even if we already
have a view with the same name.
Second you'll have to add a name.
Typically we assign views with the names starting with V underscore or W underscore to indicate the
object is a view.
Let's call our view the department employee.
Latest date.
OK don't forget to type the as keyword before you expose the final part of the query which is a select
statement.
Namely this select statement will extract data from the base table that will populate the view
as we run the select statement separately
we obtain the tabular output that our view delivers every time when implemented
OK.
Apparently we managed to retrieve a three column table with the last from and to dates registered for
each employee as defined by a max function alright.
Let's execute this query and create our view.
Perfect any signs the operation was carried out smoothly.
Apart from the green circle here.
Well look at the schema section at the left side of the screen and expand the subsection of the Employees
table.
You can see four object types one of which is Vu's the two small icons located to the right of its name
provide certain information about it.
While the last one executes the select statement embedded in the view delivering the desired result
fantastic.
As a matter of fact the view could be executed by typing the code that just appeared in the new tab.
It is a mere select statement where the database name containing the view must precede the name the
department employee.
Latest date.
This is it from a technical perspective.
We created a view that extracts the information we wanted and we use two ways to do that OK.
But why in general do we need views.
Doing that probably seemed redundant.
Can't we just run the select statement and obtain the desired output well.
Imagine your database is used by a large web application being accessed by many users.
If you would like to allow each user to see this table instead of typing and running the queue Well
statement that extracts the required information every time a request from a user appears.
The view can allow each user to see the result set on their user space a view x as a shortcut for writing
the same select statement every time a new request has been made.
Thus it saves a lot of coding time.
Moreover because it is written only once the view occupies no extra memory.
Finally the view acts as a dynamic table because it instantly reflects data and structural changes in
the base table.
For instance if you as a data administrator must update the contract date of employee 1 0 0 0 1
when you check the view the new date value will appear.
You will need to make no additional changes in the code composing the view to conclude views are advantageous
when used logically in certain applications.
The use of use can definitely be beneficial.
Nevertheless don't forget that they are not real physical datasets meaning we cannot insert or update
the information that has already been extracted.
This should be seen as temporary virtual data tables.
Retrieving information from base tables OK that will do for now.
Thank you for watching.