Is a teacher at the beginning of the course we talked about the advantage of using relational databases.
Remember we worked on an example with the sales database where we explain how applying relational algebra
techniques to fields with identical type of information into tables can speed up retrieving data.
You didn't forget this right.
Well ladies and gentlemen this is a turning point in our Eskew Well journey in the lessons to come.
You will learn how relating Eskew will tables works in practice joins are the Cuil tools that allow
us to construct a relationship between objects.
Think about strategies that would allow us to link some of the tables in our employees data.
How can we know what information can be retrieved from the different tables and what should be the criteria
according to which we will create a relationship between two tables relational schemas are the perfect
tool that will help you find a strategy for linking tables.
Let's examine the representation of the employees database in specific.
We'll focus on the employees and the department employee tables.
Technically a join shows a result set containing fields derived from two or more tables.
So we can use a join to relate the employees and the department employee table then extract information
like employee number first and last name from the Employees table and department number and start date
of the labor contract from the department employee table.
The idea of using joins is twofold.
First we must find a related column from the two tables that contains the same type of data in our case.
This can be the employee number column.
This technique would then allow us to extract information from the two tables.
Under certain conditions based on the employee number column.
Second we will be free to add columns from these two tables to our output in our example.
We could obtain the fields we just mentioned employee number and name
department number and start contract date
great in the next video we'll show you how the JOIN syntax works.
Before that while still at this stage thinking about a strategy for retrieving data from different tables
please be very careful about the following.
The columns you use to relate tables must represent the same object such as ID but the tables you are
considering need not be logically adjacent in the relational schema an example of two logically adjacent
tables.
Are the employees and apartment manager tables
and the employees and titles tables.
The department manager table and the department employee table are not logically adjacent.
This means they can be joined to and you won't have to indicate the relationship that goes through the
Employees table and the employee number key
or through departments and the department number key.
Specifically
what is important is you have found a related column connecting the two tables.
Awesome in the videos that follow.
We will show you the most notable types of joins in my rescue.
Well to do this.
We will use two duplicate tables you have graded one of them the department's duplicate in the exercise.
After this lecture you will modify it and you will create a new table that will be a duplicate of the
department managers table hence assumed this exercise is a refresher on the Data Definition Language
part of the school syntax in our next lesson.
We will start with inner joins.
Thank you for watching.