Duplicate records also known as duplicate rows are identical rows and then Eskew will table.
This means for a pair of duplicate records the values in each column coincide.
Generally duplicate rows are not always allowed in a database or a data table.
The regular practice of many companies is to clean their data from such occurrences.
However they are sometimes encountered especially in new raw or uncontrolled data.
In this lesson we will show you a way to handle them in your queries.
As a matter of fact our data is clean does not have any duplicate rows.
Therefore we can insert one row in the department manager duplicate table that is identical with one
of the others.
Employee Number 1 1 0 2 2 8 department number 3 worked on the 21st of March 1992 and with a contract
with an indefinite end.
Apparently that's why the last value will be 9 9 9 9 0 0 1 0 1.
All right.
We will also create a duplicate row in the other table.
Let it be the ninth Department customer service great.
Let's check what happened with the two tables.
First
the table with the data about the managers is the same as we saw it in the previous two lectures with
the sole difference the employee numbered 1 1 0 2 2 8 appears there twice and how about the department's
duplicate table.
We find it in the same way we did before.
The only difference is that the customer service department is shown twice fine.
The situation is clear.
Now look at this picture.
It is a snipped photo of the output of 20 rows.
When the initial state of the two tables was used without duplicates How do you expect the new output
to change regarding the one from the picture.
Do you think the number of presented rows will be smaller equal or greater.
Let's check the output of the same query this time with the two tables containing duplicate records.
We obtain 25 rows.
What do you think these additional five rows came from.
First we don't have just one but two employees with number 1 1 0 2 2 8.
Hence 2 times the department name Human Resources is appended against them.
This gives us a single additional record compared with what we had earlier.
The remaining four extra records are at the end of this resultset the department duplicate table contains
a duplicate row for department number nine customer service.
That's why every time Department number nine from the first table is matched with department nine from
the second table two records are displayed.
That's true.
You can see each of these employees twice.
1 1 1 7 8 4 8 7 7 9 3 9 and 6 9 2 awesome whether having duplicate values is a mistake in the database
or you just don't want to see duplicate rows and query results.
Here is how to handle duplicates.
Grouped by the field that differs most among records in our case.
This will be the employee number column.
This will stack all rows that have the same employee number.
Will this return the initial output with no duplicate values.
Absolutely.
20 rows.
Perfect.
This is an important tool in your arsenal.
You cannot allow yourself to assume there are no duplicate rows in your data especially if it contains
millions of rows it would be good to get used to grouping the joins by the field that differs most among
records.
I hope you enjoyed watching this video.
See you in the next one.