We spent significant time introducing joins in the inner join type.
The benefit of doing this extensive introduction was that now you can quickly understand and learn other
types of Eskew Well joins the Venn diagram you see here allows you to visualize how the left join works.
Its output allows us to see all records from the table on the left side of the join including all matching
rows of the two tables.
That's why compared to the inner join the resultset colored in red include the rest of the area the
left table in su l terms this translates in retrieving all matching values of the two tables plus all
values from the left table that matched no values from the right table.
To clarify this concept.
Let's see an application first let's remove the duplicates from the two tables.
This would allow us to explain the types of Joines we will introduce in the next few lessons better
duplicate values and flatter output with repeating records and do not contribute to the results we obtain
meaningfully.
That is why we decided to complete the section about Joines without them practicing with duplicates
will be left as part of the exercises in this section.
So don't worry you will deal with them while proceeding with their course.
All right technically after deleting the rows in which we see the respective employee and department
numbers might ask well will delete all initial records and all their duplicates.
So to proceed we must add back the initial records.
Please don't forget to do that
ha.
Ok everything looks good now.
So do you know what else we can do.
We can load the same code we used in the previous exercise.
The joints and tax will be subject to a slight change though.
Instead of relating the two tables to the keyword join or inner join we must type left join
OK that's all that needs to be modified in the code.
Let's see what will happen when we execute this query.
It returned 26 rows 6 rows more than the 20 rows we obtain in the example about inner joints which are
the 6 rows that make the difference.
Let's check this out to start our analysis.
Please refer to the Venn diagram.
These six records represent the area filled with blue.
This is the part of the Left set where no values match with the right table.
Technically speaking.
Luckily all six records of interest are in the top part of the output.
First all four records that appear in the manager's table but are not seen in the department's table
have been retrieved.
They referred to employees with numbers 9 9 9 9 0 4 5 6 and 7.
Why are these four rows retrieved because they were registered in the table on the left but not in the
table on the right.
There are no department number values that can match these records with the table on the right since
they are an example of non-matching values from the left table.
Right.
There are two more records we must discuss the ones of department two from the left table department
manager duplicate.
They appear in the left join output.
If you remember there are no such records in the department's duplicate table.
Right
there we had information for departments 1 3 4 5 and so on until 11 and nothing about department to
the two records appear in the final left join list.
But there were no corresponding values for the department name field that can come from the table on
the right perfect.
Basically this is proof that differently from what we saw for inner joins when working with left joins
the order in which you join tables matters.
Having the managers table M or the departments table D on the left can change results completely in
the next video.
We'll provide an example of what happens when we switch the order of the two tables.
Thank you for watching.