In this video we would like to emphasize that in certain occasions the order in which you join tables
and ask you well matters let's invert the order of the tables.
We will place the department's table in the left and the department manager table on the right
rerun and ha a different output.
This was due to our swapping the direction of the two tables.
So now we will have all matching values from the two tables plus the department numbers from the department's
dutiable that match no value from the department manager duplicate table.
Therefore we can expect to see records for departments 1 10 and 11 right.
OK.
But why don't we see any of them.
The answer lies in the way we've chosen the first selection in this query.
After we inverted the order of the tables and executed the query the output changed.
But that is not so obvious.
To reorganize it properly please retrieve the department number data from the department's duplicate
table.
Not from the department manager duplicate table.
The correct way to do that is to retrieve the first selection from the first table you have set and
the JOIN syntax
good.
Now let's execute the query and check its output
great.
The picture is the opposite of the one the analysis just conducted referring to the Venn diagram.
Imagine that with this query we swapped the places of the two tables.
That's why in the results section we have only one nold department number value.
And we have data about department one that has no information about an employee number.
The latter is a consequence of the fact that we have no data about department number one in the manager
table.
All right.
And because the department's table contains no information about the second department there will be
no record about it in the resultset either.
Finally as you scroll down you'll see information about all departments from three to nine with corresponding
employee numbers and department names.
At the end as you probably expected departments 10 and 11 are quoted with no information and the remaining
two fields.
This is all fantastic.
Now let's examine a few syntactical peculiarities.
We studied inner joints in the previous lessons.
Why are they called that because the values in the output are common to the two tables and the resultset
is in the inner part of the Venn diagram.
It is the area where both circles overlap.
So outer joins must exist to the LEFT JOIN falls in this category since in the output obtained you have
data from the outer part of the Venn diagram to my point here is in this case you could also use the
keywords left outer join and you will extract an identical result.
Therefore if we rerun the query adding the keyword outer in the code the outcome will not differ from
the one we obtained earlier.
True absolutely.
We obtained an identical result.
Just remember that left join and left outer join are two interchangeable phrases from a professional
perspective.
There is no reason for typing the keyword outer here because if you are using a left join it will always
be an outer type of join.
This is like omitting the word Inner from inner join.
If you remember.
Therefore as long as it is clear what type of join will be applied it professionals prefer shorter phrases
cool.
There's one final interesting detail I'd like to add.
Left Joines can deliver a list with all records from the left table that do not match any rows from
the right table.
Put differently.
The idea is to obtain all records that appear only in the left outer blue part of the Venn diagram in
this picture.
Which are these records.
In our case
looking at the output obtained with the first left join.
These are the top six rows of the data list.
You see they have null values in the department name field and how do we get to these rows programmatically.
The trick is to include a WHERE clause.
His condition will be all department name values to be null.
So you must type where department name is null through a left join.
We will retrieve this bit of the table whose column information comes from the right table and is null.
Makes sense when you think of it doesn't it.
Let's execute the query and check if we will obtain a six row result.
Bingo Yes can't be better.
Now roll up your sleeves and have a go with the exercises attached to this lesson.
See you in the next video.