Excellent Let's apply JOIN syntax to the department manager duplicate and apartments duplicate tables
to obtain a list of records containing information about the department number the employee number and
the department name related to every manager.
I will use the letters M and D as aliases for the two tables respectively.
Knowing their content we can specify the fields we would like to see right after the select keyword.
Let's extract the department in employee numbers from the department manager duplicate table and the
department name from the department's duplicate table.
All right.
Therefore the next thing we must state are the two tables to be joined while doing that.
Please don't forget to add their aliases so we must type department manager.
Duplicate M.
careful here.
Enter join as this is the type of join we are implementing.
And finally deps duplicate de
awesome.
To conclude the JOIN syntax we must specify the columns relating the two tables.
Remember let's do that by typing on and then equalising or conceptually matching the department number
column from the first table with that column bearing the same name from the second table.
These are the department number field from the department manager duplicate table and the department
number field from the department's duplicate table.
I would like to remind you that the relating columns of the two tables need not be named in the same
way.
However it helps avoid confusion and is more convenient if they do.
That's why in our example both fields carry the same name before running this interesting query.
Order the results according to the department number.
This will improve the outputs representation.
Since we obtained this column from the department manager duplicate table.
We will sort the information in the order by clause by the department number from the YM table.
All right let's execute this query and see what will obtain 20 rows of information.
Let's check the retrieve data.
We have data about the departments from 3 to 9 only.
There is no data about departments one to 10 or 11 or about the ones labeled as null values.
Why is this happening.
Inner joins.
Extract only records in which the values in the related columns match no values or values appearing
and just one of the two tables and not appearing in the other are not displayed.
Let's analyze the outcome by examining the tables row by row.
The department manager duplicate has a few no value department numbers and has no information about
Department 1 10 and 11 therefore inner joins do not present no values.
The first four rows do not appear in the inner join.
We executed
OK.
We have 26 records in this table all together and 26 minus four gives us 22.
Hence there must be two records in the inner join we do not see because it displayed only 20 rows.
Now we can recheck the content of the department's duplicate table.
It has a null value department.
Number two do we see it in the inner join output.
No we don't.
And why didn't SU well match the null values of the first table with this null value here.
Because it would make no sense only non-North matching values are in play.
Moving further department number two doesn't participate in any record.
Do we have it in the department manager duplicate table.
Yes we do.
There are two records with it in there.
And namely these were the two records we did not see in the final output.
There were no values from the department's duplicate table to be matched with them in the inner join
awesome.
Finally the department's duplicate table has two more records.
They are of departments 10 and 11.
But as we mentioned they have no values to be matched with from the department manager duplicate table.
These two rows are dropped from the outcome.
Great.
I hope this analysis makes it clearer and explains why we say an inner join is represented by the common
area of the two circles in the Venn diagram.
This area is namely the set of the matching values of both tables which are the only ones displayed
in the inner join output.
And what if such matching values did not exist simply the result set will be empty.
There will be no link between the two tables.
Thanks for watching.