In this lesson we'll provide you with a few notes on using joints not just inner joins but any types
of joins.
First we saw that in the output we can select different columns from the tables we are referencing in
the last example we chose the department and employee numbers from the managers duplicate table and
the department name from the department's duplicate table.
We could have also added the starting and ending date of managers contracts.
Let's check for him from date
and him to date
100 percent.
So we may add any combination of columns we'd like in our output.
The only condition is that each column must be part of one of the join tables.
A second note I would like to share with you is that some people prefer typing the code in the from
block first so they specify in advance.
All alias's they will need in the rest of the query.
For instance they would first type from department manager duplicate M. inner join departments duplicate
De on the equality of the two department numbers.
Then they will specify the selections of interest inserting the field names with the help of the assigned
aliases.
This might be helpful if you are joining more than 2 tables.
But in my opinion one can get used to remembering a few letters and follow the top down flow of the
query anyway.
The order to be followed is that the coders discretion.
What matters is if the query you've written is correct.
All right as far as the inner join syntax is concerned the word enter is not obligatory.
It could be omitted in this query whether you type inner join or just join.
It makes no difference as Cuil will always understand you are talking about an inner join.
This is what practitioners would typically do.
That's why we will use join instead of inner join another issue a novice Eskew Well programmer could
encounter is whether the order in which you specify the matching columns matters.
Meaning is there any difference between typing M department number equals D department number.
And d department number equals M department number no.
There is no difference.
It is up to you.
I use the table first and the detail second to avoid confusion with the order in which I designated
the two tables to be joined
and this might be a very useful trick as you will see in the next lectures.
Otherwise from a technical perspective there is no difference OK.
Good let's focus on the order by clause.
Do you remember we sorted the output we obtained according to the department number from the managers
duplicate table.
Technically this query will work if you remove the table indication
or if you change it to the department's duplicate table.
The point here is that it is not obvious why we use him an apartment number and not something else.
But you will appreciate this little detail when you advance and work with much larger data sets procedures
indexes and other tools.
Unless you use this notation when indicating the column and the department managers duplicate table
ask you well will display an error.
I hope that after going through these notes you feel you have joined the rescue community in the next
video.
We will show you what duplicate records are and how to deal with them.
Thank you for watching.