Rollback to start this section we will refer to the transaction controlling which lecture you saw at
the very beginning of the course where we explain how Committee can be used to save the state of the
data and the database.
At the moment of its execution rollback.
On the other hand is a command that can bring the state of the data a step back but not more than that
it will refer to the state corresponding to the last time you executed commit.
This means if you have already used commit 10 times rollback will have an effect on the last execution
you have performed after that moment.
Even if you run the rollback clause 20 times you can get to the state of only the last commit you cannot
restore data to a state corresponding to an earlier commit.
In a nutshell these are the rules regarding transaction control.
We must be very careful when using commit and rollback.
In other words when we are changing the state of our data set.
Please note that it will be very hard to practice these statements unless we switch off the following
feature of workbench.
We can expand the edit tab from the main menu and opt for preferences on the left hand side of the window
that pops up choose the editor section on the right hand side.
Scroll down to get to the box that says safe updates through the ticking of this option.
The software could prevent you from losing significant amounts of data or some of the changes you made
earlier.
However it could also eliminate the possibility of controlling the state of the data in our database.
None of these two features will help us here though.
That's why we will continue without enabling this option.
Please turn it off.
Great.
And please remember that after turning off the safe updates option you must be very careful when updating
and deleting data.
In my view well one can always make a simple mistake that could result in the loss of a large amount
of data.
That's not what we want to happen is it OK.
One last thing to properly switch off the safe updates reconnection to the database is required.
So let's exit this connection.
And then reconnect typing the password once again.
Lovely.
Now we are ready to dive into the update statement lecture.
See you there.