All right here we go in the previous section we inserted an employee under the number of 9 9 9 9 0 1.
Remember in here we will update this record the update statement would allow us to do that.
It is used to update the values of existing records in a table.
The syntax to adhere to is update table name.
The keyword set column names and the respective values assigned to them.
And finally where it is certain condition or set of conditions that must be satisfied by using this
code structure as well will change the record or records satisfying the WHERE condition.
Updating the old values of the columns listed with the new ones ok.
We can see that employee number 9 9 9 9 0 1 is John Smith.
So we can create a query with the following update statement
update employees set and then assign the value of the string Stela to the first name column the string
Parkinson to the last name column.
The thirty first of December 1992 birthdate and F to gender the condition here is to have an employee
number that equals John Smith's number 9 9 9 9 0 1.
This means as you will optimizer will so to speak access the record with Employee Number 9 9 9 9 0 1
and substitute the existing values with the new ones indicated in the update statement.
Note that we did not update the higher date column value right.
Moreover Eskew well showed no error because of that.
This is fine as we do not have to update each value of the record of interest.
Of course we can still say we have updated the specific record okay.
We can finally run this query.
After that we will select the same employee through the employee number once again.
Let's see what happens.
We see Stella Parkinson there not John Smith with a different birth date and gender although with the
same higher date.
Great.
Please note the following feature of the update statement.
Had we used a non-existent condition in the WHERE clause for instance an employee number of 9 9 9 9
0 9 my rescue well would have allowed the execution of the queery.
Given that they ask you well syntax is correct.
Nevertheless nothing would have happened.
The statement would have worked.
Affecting 0 rows because the table doesn't contain an employee with such a number at the moment of the
queries execution
awesome stay focused for another interesting feature we will discuss in the second part of this lesson.
Thank you for watching.