When updating your table the WHERE clause is crucial although by default and my skew Well it is set
to be optional if you don't provide a WHERE condition all rows of the table will be updated.
Check what we have in the department's duplicate table.
Nine rows into columns with information good for the sake of this exercise we will change all the department
numbers and names in this table.
Right before that we will execute a commit command.
It will save the data set as we see it.
Now if we write the code that updates the department duplicate table setting a department number equal
to 1 1 and a department name quality control and then run it we will modify all rows of the data table.
Is this true.
Let's see.
Absolutely.
Deps duplicate is a table now comprising identical rows.
This would typically happen by mistake when the where clause and the accompanying conditions have not
been added.
If we've done this by accident is there a way to go back.
Of course we can do that by applying the rollback command when executed.
It will take us to the last comment that has been run or if we have not run a commit command beforehand
it will take us to the beginning of the entire rescue code and we will potentially lose hours of work.
That's why it is important to commit the changes we made a minute ago.
Remember you should be careful when using this command because once you execute commit you can not reverse
any change.
So after running rollback Where will we go back to let's check
perfect.
We see the information we had in the department's duplicate table at the beginning of this lecture assume
we need the current version of this table for our next lecture.
Thus it will be very important to execute another commit statement here let's do it.
Fantastic.
What we can infer from the lessons about the update statement is that you will rarely have to update
an entire table rather you'll have to indicate the exact condition that must be satisfied.
If you don't you risk turning your data set into a mess.
So please be very careful in setting a condition in the WHERE clause of the update statement.
Wonderful.
Next we will deal with the delete statement.
Thanks for watching.