In this lesson we will see all sub queries can be incorporated within as well queries as their name
suggests some queries are queries embedded in a query.
They are also called Inner queries or nested queries and they are part of another query called an outer
query alternative names for these rescue features our inner select an outer select respectively sub
queries can be applied in many ways.
Nevertheless the main idea is the same most often a sub query is employed in the WHERE clause of a select
statement.
Let's see an example as we run this query.
We retrieved 24 records which means 24 people currently work in the enterprise as managers.
If our database is in perfect condition the same 24 people must be registered in the Employees table
where we can find different information about them.
So I assume you are interested in obtaining the names of all employees working within the enterprise
as managers.
Keep in mind that names can be found only in the Employees table not in the department manager table.
There are a few ways you could obtain the design the desired result.
We will try the one involving the use of sub queries as it will allow us to extract the required information
from the first table.
So long as the same employees have been registered in the department manager table
let's check the relevant syntax.
We select the first and last name from the Employees table for the same employee numbers that can be
found in the department manager table.
The last condition has been set through the where clause in the in operator which you already know how
to use.
It will list all employee numbers recorded in the department manager table.
After we execute this query we will be able to verify the data about all 24 managers has been stored
in the Employees table as well great.
Let's analyze this example.
First the outer query is the entire code starting from select first name last name and so on until the
in operator
the sub query or the inner query that is nested within the outer query.
Is this little bit here.
Remember a sub query should always be placed within parentheses.
In this case we should make no exception to this rule as well.
From a processing point of view the fuel engine starts by running the inner query that it uses its return
output which is intermediate to execute the outer query.
In general a sub query may return a single value a scalar a single row a single column or an entire
table.
In our case it delivers the entire employee number column from the department manager table.
Actually to prove this is the case we could run the sub query as a standalone query
after we execute this bit of code.
We obtain the employee number column the way we should have
fantastic although we will not dive into tasks that are too complex.
Please remember you can have a lot more than one sub query in your outer query.
It is possible to nest in her queries within other inner queries thus allowing your analysis to achieve
significant depth.
In that case the Cuil engine would execute the innermost query first and then each subsequent query
until it runs the outermost query.
Last Stay tuned for the next video in which we will see another example of a query containing a sub
query that will do for now.
Thank you for watching.