There is another logical operator we need to introduce as it is related strictly to using some queries.
The exists operator checks whether certain row values are found within a sub query.
This Jack is conducted row by row.
It returns a boolean value if a row value of a sub query exists.
The operator returns true and the corresponding record of the outer query is extracted.
Otherwise exists returns false and no row value from the outer query is extracted.
Here's an example.
It will deliver all first and last names of the people in the Employees table who are also found in
the department manager table as a matter of fact will create a whole table not just a column as we did
with the in operator
OK.
It contains 24 rows
obviously the exits and the operators resemble each other when applied to some queries.
Here is the substantial difference between the two.
It is noticeable particularly when working on large web mobile or business applications.
We're visualizing data quickly is crucial.
Exists Tesauro values for existence while in searches among values hence exists is quicker in retrieving
large amounts of data while in is faster with smaller data sets.
Awesome.
Let me make a short side note about using order by in the context of nested queries in my rescue.
Well you can order the result list by employee number and insert the order by clause within the sub
query.
Of course the query will run properly
the outer query will simply follow the order of the inner query.
However it is more professional to apply order by in the outer query.
So please try to get used to leaving this clause in the outer select.
It is more acceptable logically to sort the final version of your dataset and not versions preceding
the final one.
Great.
Be aware that some though not all nested queries can be rewritten using joins which are more efficient
in general.
This is true particularly for inner queries using the WHERE clause.
Although sometimes the same answers can be obtained with a join nested queries are considered an essential
tool and that's why you must learn them on certain occasions.
Sub queries can be bad for performance concerns but here's why people would still need to use them.
First they allow for better structuring of the outer query.
Thus each inner query can be thought of in isolation and organizing the extraction process can be improved.
Hence the name of Eskew well structured query language second.
In some situations the use of sub queries is much more intuitive compared to the use of complex joins
and unions.
Finally many users prefer sub queries simply because they offer enhanced code readability great.
This will do for now.
Thank you for watching.