Aweary.
Right.
So some queries can be executed within a select statement or with a FROM clause as well not just with
the WHERE clause.
This means they can be placed pretty much anywhere in a query.
So long as it makes sense to do so.
In my opinion you have advanced with as well a lot at this point.
Congratulations for that.
That's why in this lecture we're not going to keep things simple.
We are going to complete a challenging task together based on that.
After the video you will face an exercise that is much harder.
However it is of paramount importance not just because you will solidify the knowledge gained in this
video and as you well in general but we will use its output in our next lecture which is about self
joins OK.
Having said that let's begin here's the task assigned employee number 1 1 0 0 0 22.
As a manager to all employees from 1 0 0 0 1 2 1 0 0 20 or from 1 to 24 brief and Employee Number 1
1 0 0 39.
As a manager to all employees from 21 to 40 good the result is a mixture of two subsets of results.
The first one is subset A.
It will be the Group of the first 20 employees associated with manager 1 1 0 0 22.
The second one will call subset B.
It will contain data about the employees assigned to manager 1 1 0 0 39 the unification between the
two subsets will be made through a union and the tables from which we will be extracting data will be
employees and department manager.
All right.
So let's start from the innermost query of the first block.
This is the code that would allow us to select the employee with number 1 1 0 0 22 from the department
manager table.
It is easy to understand now we will add this inner query to the select statement of an outer query.
The outcome of this bigger block must be a table with an employee ID department code and a manager ID.
In addition all employee IDs will be smaller than 1 0 0 20.
Let's type the code we need.
We will select the employee number as Employee ID
and the minimum value of a department number as department code.
We take the minimum value because more than one department could be associated with an employee and
by using men we will ensure we place only one value corresponding to an employee number.
At this point we'll have to use the sub query of the select statement.
As usual we will place the content of the sub query within parentheses and add an alias.
By doing this we end the select part of the outer query lovely OK this means we must proceed with from.
And the other clauses will need to use
you are quite familiar with the structure needed to complete the remaining part of the code so we won't
analyze it in detail.
Basically what we are doing here is joining the employees in the department manager tables where no
employee number is greater than 1 0 0 20.
All right let's execute the query.
Great.
We obtained the 20 row table we wanted.
Perfect.
We will proceed by inserting this entire code within the from statement of an even outer query.
It will be the last level of queering.
So we will not go further out if it makes sense to say so in as well terms.
This will be a small step.
All we have to do is surround the code with parentheses rename it.
Subset A and attach it after select everything from A
and from.
This is how you can use a sub query or an inner query in the From statement of an outer query.
Let's see if it works properly
yes it does.
However the output was in no way different from the one we obtained earlier.
That's OK because at this stage we don't need to retrieve additional data.
We needed to give a name to this set which will be a subset in the bigger query we will create in a
minute.
Hence all we did here is create an output called a awesome.
Finally we must combine this subset with the other one.
We will call be.
We all use the same code and then type union.
What follows is an identically structured piece of code that will bring subset before us.
That's all we will need to accomplish our task.
We will not create b separately.
Let's first copy and paste what we have for a
now.
We will edit only the lines that will bring the desired outcome.
We said we needed manager 1 1 0 0 39.
So we can change the conditional value in the inner most select.
Furthermore we would like to have 20 people who are different from the ones provided by subset A.
So we will change the where condition to greater than 1 0 0 20 finally because we said these employees
must be 20 we can add a limit 20 at the end.
And when we rename this entire block to be and add a semi-colon we will be done.
Is this true.
Absolutely.
A task that looks so simple required almost 50 lines of code.
Amazing when you are writing queries as long as this one.
Please pay particular attention to the indentation.
If all rows started from the same horizontal position the code would have been hard to read.
That's why it is essential to begin each sub query level with an indent to the right
well then I hope you will agree that writing a 50 row query is not that scary.
I'm confident that coding step by step you can do that too.
Please feel free to rewind this video if necessary and to change the code to obtain similar or different
output when you feel you are well acquainted with the topic of sub queries.
Move on to the exercise attached.
It will be challenging and will deliver the table we need for our next video.
Thank you for watching.