Welcome to another chapter of this course so far you have spent a significant amount of time studying
as well the last few sections introduced you to the language is practical application in which data
manipulation was our core focus.
It's time to take a step forward in the next lectures.
You will be dealing with aggregate functions what are they.
We already introduced them in the select section.
Their name derives from the fact that they gather data from many rows of a table then aggregate it into
a single value as we explained earlier.
This means the information contained in multiple rows will be the input of these functions and the single
value they provide is the respective output.
There are other aggregate functions besides count those that are used most often are some min max and
average abbreviated avy.
This is because of their ability to return a single value from an entire column.
Another way to refer to aggregate functions is as summarizing functions.
Why do these functions exist.
They are responsible to the information requirements of a companys different organizational levels.
A businesses top management executives are typically interested in summarized figures and rarely in
detail.
Data in such situations aggregate functions are the perfect solution.
Let's focus on the salary table instead of checking the DDL statement.
We can use select to extract a brief 10 row output that will show us that in this table we have information
about employee numbers salaries and starting and ending dates of employment.
Great we can use the Count function to count the number of salaries contracts in this data table.
Please remember that the name of the column salary acts as an argument of the Count function by running
the query will take approximately 967 thousand records.
OK remember that count is applicable to both numeric and non-numeric data.
If your boss would like to know how many employees start dates are in the database you can use count
from date and obtain the result.
By the way why do we have the same number.
Because the length of both columns is the same and we don't have missing data in either of them.
Great.
Finally we talked about count distinct.
Remember this addition helps us find the number of times unique values are encountered in a given column.
Therefore count distinct from date will deliver the answer to the question your boss asked
contracts have been signed on six thousand three hundred and ninety two different dates.
Now's the right time to introduce another interesting feature on the count function.
Earlier we mentioned that aggregate functions typically ignore null values throughout the field to which
they are applied.
Actually this can happen only if you have indicated a specific column name within the parentheses.
The alternative option you can choose is typing the star wildcard character not preceding it by the
keyword distinct.
This is a special feature of the Count function that returns the number of all rows of the table null
values included.
So by writing a specific column name or a star symbol within the parentheses you will define whether
null values are taken into account.
A final note is that the parentheses in the argument must be attached to the name of the aggregate function.
In other words you shouldn't leave whitespace before opening the parentheses.
If you do your query won't work good in the next video.
We will learn how to use some.
See you there.