Okay perfect the next function we'll consider is average abbreviated as Avi G.
It extracts the average value of all non-null values in a field.
Not surprisingly the queries structure is identical to the one employed for all aggregate functions.
Up to this moment.
Just remember to use the function name.
G if you typed the entire word average for example the query won't work.
All right let's calculate the average annual price of a contract in the employees database which is
the same as asking ourselves which is the average annual salary that company's employee received
OK.
All we have to do is execute and
here's the number.
Approximately sixty three thousand seven hundred sixty one dollars and twenty cents this concludes the
introduction of aggregate functions in my ask you Will.
Please don't forget that aggregate functions can be applied to any group of data values within a certain
column.
This is another reason they are frequently used together with a group by clause.
Are examples here did not contain queries long enough to include a group by block.
We intended to present the aggregate functions without additional complexity.
I promise you that later in the course we will look at more sophisticated examples involving aggregate
functions.
By the way it's a bit annoying to see four digits after the decimal point isn't it.
You probably expect to see only two representing the number of cents in the price right.
Maybe you wish you could around this value somehow.
Yes you can in the next section we will show you how to do that and as well as several other operations
that will help you work in as well.
Thanks for watching.