Round is a numeric or math function you can use in my ask you.
Well it is usually applied to the single values that aggregate functions return.
Look at the average value we obtained in the previous video assume you don't want to show dollar amounts
and since then that you would like to present the number as a whole integer.
This will be an easy task for the round function.
Its syntax is very simple.
It embraces its argument which is the number that must be rounded round can be located anywhere in the
query as long as the numeric value has been provided within the parentheses.
In our case rounds should precede the average function together with its argument.
Let's run the query to see what we get.
Awesome.
The same number rounded to the closest integer.
Sixty three thousand seven hundred sixty one.
Fantastic.
In addition don't forget that you can have a second argument of the round function after average salary.
You can put a comma and add a number which will equal the number of digits you see after the decimal
point of the value in your output.
Here given that the aggregate function gives us an average of a monetary value it makes sense to round
the result to a value with a precision of since.
Let's say two digits after the decimal point would be a satisfactory result.
This code complies with the syntax required.
Let's execute it and see if we obtain what we want
100 percent.
Sixty three thousand seven hundred sixty one dollars and twenty cents excellent in our next lesson.
We will study another built in function which is considered in advanced as Cuil tool.
It is called coalesce.
Thank you for watching.