Consider the output we obtained in the previous lecture Let's see what you can do if you are unhappy
with the Noall label and would like to have a different sign or text displayed when there is a missing
value.
For instance if we lack data for the department name field and we would like to see Department name
not provided instead of gnoll how can we do that in my school.
A function called if NULL can be employed within this select block and needs only two arguments within
its parentheses.
If null function works in the following way it returns the first of the two indicated values.
If the data value found in the table is not normal and returns the second value if there is a null value
then it prints the return value in the column of the output.
The following example better illustrates how if null works in practice we can select the department
number column and it will be projected as the first column in our output table.
Then after a comma instead of simply placing the department in field we can add it within the parentheses
of the if not all function.
In this case if the value of a certain record in department name is null we will see the string we are
about to insert after the comma department name not provided.
If the department name field is not null we will see the initial data value.
Awesome.
Let's run this query to see the result
exactly what we wanted.
Great.
At this point only one thing is a bit annoying.
This whole line shouldn't be a column name.
Wouldn't you agree.
What do you think.
Can we rename this column to department name and rerun the query.
Boom.
Much better.
This is a decent output and still deliver the expected result.
Of course if no has its limitations it cannot contain more than two parameters.
This is where coalesce steps in.
It allows you to insert in arguments in the parentheses you can think of coalesce as if gnoll with more
than two parameters.
By definition coalesce will always return a single value of the ones we have within parentheses and
this value will be the first non-null value of this list.
Reading the values from left to right as a result if coalesce has two arguments it will work precisely
like if null.
Let's verify this by substituting a function name and re executing the query
the output we obtained is identical.
Awesome Let's see all coalesce works when we have three arguments.
The function we have here points to the third column and it will contain three arguments.
Our idea is to see in each cell of the third column the initial value of that cell if it is not null
to see the department name value if it is null.
And finally to see an in a string if the second designated value department name is null
so because all values in the third column are null we should expect to have the second column replicated
in place of the third one except for the last couple of rows where we should have any OK let's run this
query and analyze the output
great.
The first section of our query is the department number and then we have a department name Next consider
the first row of the third column.
It makes us think about the three arguments of the coalesce function.
The first argument is No it is the initial value of the department manager column.
But as you remember the entire column was empty.
So what does coalesce do.
It simply moves on until it finds a non-null value right.
Therefore coalesce so to speak skips the value of the first argument and proceeds to check the value
of the second argument.
It is the value of the department name field.
Do we have any information there yes.
The name of the Department of the first record is marketing.
So coalesce stops here and says Here is a non-null value of one of my arguments.
This is the one I am going to display.
This is why marketing is displayed as a value in the third column.
Fantastic.
Now please consider the last row department number 11 the department name has not been registered.
Hence we see no value as a result in the last row of the third column.
Coalesce will work like this.
First it will check the initial value of the department manager and understand that it is null then
it will check the value of the department name which is null again.
So what's next.
Coalesce we'll see whether any arguments are enlisted within the parentheses and will check their values.
We have one more in a.
This is a non-null string value and that's why coalesce displays it in the last row of the third field.
Great.
Remember one very important thing about coalesce and if Noal they do not make any changes to the data
set they merely create an output where certain data values appear in place of null values.
Thanks for watching.