There is another interesting way in which we can use coalesce.
We can have a single argument in a given function.
How should it be interpreted.
Quite simply the value indicated as an argument will be displayed technically.
And this example coalesced was used to show one additional column and the output practitioners find
this trick useful of some hypothetical result must be provided in a supplementary column.
In our situation we saw how the apartment manager name appears in all records of the fake column.
This way if you are still building the table and perhaps the database coalesce can help you visualize
a prototype of the tables final version and thus consider whether to create a real column containing
the department manager's name.
Finally please remember that this trick is carried out with coalesce only if you substitute it with
if no.
For example workbench will display an error because if Noal works with precisely two arguments while
coalesce can have one two or more arguments.
For this reason on most occasions professionals prefer using coalesce instead of if null with this we
conclude our aggregate forget functions S..
In our next section we will study Joines one of the most powerful and handy tools in my rescue well
and Eskew Well in general.
Thank you for watching.