End.
Right.
So now that you know what aggregate functions are about and how to use the first of them count we are
ready to introduce the next one.
Let's all the values in the salaries column to see how much money the firm spent on salaries.
All we have to do is use some instead of count and designate the salary column as an argument.
Let's run this query.
Boom a huge number.
Don't spend too much time reading the result.
Trust me it's larger than 61 billion.
Wow.
For the sake of this exercise let's replace the field name indicated in parentheses with this star symbol.
Do you think workbench will sum all numbers from the salaries table.
No it would rather raise a syntax error.
That's proof.
The star symbol feature goes well with only the count function.
It doesn't work with other aggregate functions.
Overall remember that count can be applied to both numeric and non-numeric data differently some.
And the remaining aggregate functions average men and Max work only with numeric data.
You can't use them with non-numeric data in the next lecture will show you how to use max and man.
Thank you for watching.