Or you.
OK.
So max and min return the maximum and minimum value of the column.
If you're asking yourself wait which is the highest salary we offer you will need the maximum value
from the salary column would you placing it right after the select keyword.
The max function can retrieve this value for you then conclude by from salaries in a semi-colon.
Let's run the query to see the result.
Well the highest salary paid by the company is one hundred fifty eight thousand two hundred twenty dollars
per annum.
Not bad.
And which is the lowest contract value in the company hopefully of an intern or a young newcomer to
get the answer.
Substitute the max function with men without doing anything with the rest of the code in the query execute
thirty eight thousand seven hundred and thirty five dollars.
As you can see Min returns the lowest from the list of numeric values.
Great in our next video we'll learn about the average function.
Thank you for watching.